# ARTHUR D BAILEY

### **EDUCATION**

MBA Business Administration,

University of Colorado at Boulder



# ( Time Management



# Leadership 👺

# **SKILLS**

## Software Product Manager

+1-085-339-5061 @ elonmusk@fakemail.com @ linkedin.com/in/arthur.bailey

San Fransisco, CA

### SUMMARY

Software Product Manager with a solid foundation in Computer Science. My experience is not limited to just managing teams of developers and designers, but also helping them develop apps from scratch. The achievement that I am most proud of is growing Pinterest from 30M users to 120M in 1 year by adding a feature based on user feedback.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Product Manager

2018 - Ongoing

Spotify

San Fransisco, CA

Spotify is a Swedish audio streaming and media services provider. It is one of the world's largest music streaming service providers, with over 356 million monthly active users and 58 million paying subscribers.

- Increased conversion rates of trial users to paid accounts by 45% after implementing an 80% summer subscription discount in 2018-2019
- Managing record label partnerships: increased revenue with 20% by negotiating deals
- Scrum master of a 20-person back-end developer team
- Redesigned the whole back-end of Spotify with Python, reducing loading times by 40%
- Conducted Competitive & Market Research and raised the Family Subscription price by \$1 in 2021, bringing a 25% increase in profits in the first half of 2021

### 2014 - 2018 **Product Manager**

**Pinterest** 

San Fransisco, CA

Pinterest is an American image sharing and social media service designed to enable saving

and discovery of information on the Internet. Increased average length of user retention by 30% by updating the UI

- Conducted a customer survey among 200K users about any new features they would like to see on Pinterest
- Gathered the data and pitched it in front of key stakeholders
- Managed the development of the Pinterest Chrome Add-on as a Scrum master of an 8person team of devs and designers
- The Save to Pinterest Add-on grew the platform by 75%, reaching 120M users in fall 2018

# App Development Manager

2011 - 2014

McDonald's UK

London, UK

McDonald's Corporation is an American fast food company with locations all around the globe. I managed the development of the McDonald's mobile app.

- Managed a 15-person team of developers and designers
- Conducted Competitive Research and gathered data about what features the McDonald's app must have and what features we can improve
- Created a Product Roadmap and set a goal to launch the app in 6 months
- Finished development 1 week short from the deadline
- Created a social media campaign for the launch of our mobile-app which drove 10,000 installations on the release date
- Built Python apps that allowed developers to build proprietary solutions without requiring standard components

